<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AUG Signals Hellas</title>
    <link>http://www.gsa-hsa.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on AUG Signals Hellas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2015</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 16:53:52 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.gsa-hsa.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About GSA</title>
      <link>http://www.gsa-hsa.github.io/posts/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 16:53:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gsa-hsa.github.io/posts/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mission-statement-and-mandate:d680e8a854a7cbad6d490c445cba2eba&#34;&gt;Mission Statement and Mandate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Greek Space Agency is committed to promoting scientific advancement in space technologies, via collaboration with local and international industry and academia, while ensuring the realization of economic, industrial and social benefits for Greece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;collaborators:d680e8a854a7cbad6d490c445cba2eba&#34;&gt;Collaborators&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pictures await&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Board of Directors</title>
      <link>http://www.gsa-hsa.github.io/posts/about/board-of-directors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 16:53:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gsa-hsa.github.io/posts/about/board-of-directors/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dr-george-a-lampropoulos-president:8e1b4e6891b85468515b3e2b8f66201a&#34;&gt;Dr. George A. Lampropoulos &amp;ndash; President&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/board_members/lampro.png&#34; alt=&#34;George Lampropoulos&#34; title=&#34;George Lampropoulos&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. George A. Lampropoulos has held the position of President with the Greek Space Agency since 2006. Dr. Lampropoulos holds a BSc from the University of Patras (Greece), and an MSc and a PhD from Queen&amp;rsquo;s University (Kingston, Ontario, Canada), all in Electrical Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Lampropoulos is an internationally recognized expert in the area of signal processing, having chaired several sessions of SPIE conferences, published/edited 13 books, and written and co-written over 200 papers in scientific journals and conference proceedings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Lampropoulos has taught at the University of Toronto (Ontario, Canada), Laval University (Quebec, Canada) and Royal Military College of Canada (Kingston, Ontario), and is also the founder, President and CEO of A.U.G. Signals Ltd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dr-maria-petrou-secretary-general:8e1b4e6891b85468515b3e2b8f66201a&#34;&gt;Dr. Maria Petrou &amp;ndash; Secretary-General&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/board_members/petrou.png&#34; alt=&#34;Maria Petrou&#34; title=&#34;Maria Petrou&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Maria Petrou passed away in 2012. Her position remains vacant currently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Maria Petrou, FREng, DSc, PhD, FCGI, FIAPR, FIET, FIoP, FBMVA, was the Director of the Informatics and Telematics Institute (ITI) of the Centre of Research and Technology, Hellas (CERTH), Professor of Signal Processing, Imperial College London, and founding member of GSA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She served as the Chairman of the Technical Committee for Remote Sensing of the International Association of Pattern Recognition (IAPR), the Chairman of the British Machine Vision Association, as the Treasurer of IAPR, as a Trustee of the Institution of Engineering and Technology (IET), an Associate Editor of IEEE Transactions on Image Processing, as the Newsletter Editor of IAPR, as an editor of IEE Electronics Letters, as a Theme Leader for the Data and Information Fusion Defense Technology Centre, and as a member of many advisory boards and committees. She had published more than 350 scientific papers, three books, and had supervised to successful completion 41 PhD theses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dr-vassilis-anastassopoulos-vice-secretary-general:8e1b4e6891b85468515b3e2b8f66201a&#34;&gt;Dr. Vassilis Anastassopoulos &amp;ndash; Vice-Secretary General&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/board_members/anastasso.png&#34; alt=&#34;Vassilis Anastassopoulos&#34; title=&#34;Vassilis Anastassopoulos&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Vassilis Anastassopoulos received a BSc degree in Physics PhD in Electronics from the University of Patras, Greece. With over 80 published journal and conference papers, he worked for two years at various Canadian scientific institutions, and has been an academic staff member in Physics Department, University of Patras, Greece from 1987, having received full professorship in 2005. Dr. Anastassopoulos is currently the Vice Rector for Strategic Research Planning and Development with the University of Patras.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Anastassopoulos&amp;rsquo;s research interests are within the scope of digital signal processing, image processing, radar signal processing and remote sensing with emphasis on multi-spectral, SAR and infrared imagery, signal detection, pattern recognition, and information fusion including image fusion, decision fusion and sensor fusion architectures. In the last few years he has been involved in image processing techniques for astro-particle physics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;prof-nikolaos-uzunoglu-vice-prsesident:8e1b4e6891b85468515b3e2b8f66201a&#34;&gt;Prof. Nikolaos Uzunoglu &amp;ndash; Vice Prsesident&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/board_members/uzunoglu.png&#34; alt=&#34;Nikolaos Uzunoglu&#34; title=&#34;Nikolaos Uzunoglu&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professor Nikolaos Uzunoglu carried his PhD in the field of propagation phenomena in satellite links in 1970&amp;rsquo;s and continued research and teaching at the National Technical University of Athens on the topics of Applied Electromagnetism, Telecommmunications, Radar Systems, Microwave and RF Systems, Antennas and applications of Electromagnetism in Biomedical Engineering. The Microwave and Fiber Optics Laboratory he directs is involved in numerous European Projects. He has coordinated the &amp;ldquo;Rural Wings&amp;rdquo; Integrated European Commission project concerning the pilot wide application of broadband satellite telecommunications to serve the needs of isolated communitites all over the Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dr-vassilis-tsagaris-treasurer:8e1b4e6891b85468515b3e2b8f66201a&#34;&gt;Dr. Vassilis Tsagaris &amp;ndash; Treasurer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/board_members/tsagaris.png&#34; alt=&#34;Vassilis Tsagaris&#34; title=&#34;Vassilis Tsagaris&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vassilis Tsagaris received his BSc degree in Physics in 1997, his MSc in Electronics in 2000, and PhD in data fusion and remote sensing in 2006, all from the University of Patras. His research work is in the fields of image processing, data and sensor fusion and pattern recognition. He has published more than 20 journal and conference papers and participated in several national and European RTD projects. He serves as a reviewer for IEEE and SPIE journals and for European projects in the framework of the ARTEMISIA JTI. Today, he works in IRIDA Labs as Head of the Earth Observation Unit and as a post-doc researcher in the University of Patras.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dr-dimitris-manolakis-trustee:8e1b4e6891b85468515b3e2b8f66201a&#34;&gt;Dr. Dimitris Manolakis &amp;ndash; Trustee&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/board_members/default.png&#34; alt=&#34;Dimitris Manolakis&#34; title=&#34;Dimitris Manolakis&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dimitris G. Manolakis attended the University of Athens, where he received a BS in physics and PhD in electrical engineering. He is currently a member of the technical staff at MIT Lincoln Laboratory, in Lexington, Massachusetts. Dr. Manolakis has taught at the University of Athens, Northeastern University, Boston College, and Worcester Polytechnic Institute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dr-athansios-potsis-vice-trustee:8e1b4e6891b85468515b3e2b8f66201a&#34;&gt;Dr. Athansios Potsis &amp;ndash; Vice Trustee&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/board_members/potsis.png&#34; alt=&#34;Athansios Potsis&#34; title=&#34;Athansios Potsis&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Thanasis Potsis holds a PhD degree in Electrical &amp;amp; Computer Engineering from the National Technical University of Athens, Greece. He also holds a Diploma in Electrical &amp;amp; Computer Technology from the University of Patras - Polytechnic School. Dr. Potsis is a Member and a scientific paper reviewer of IEEE, as well as of the Technical Chamber of Greece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Potsis has worked at German Aerospace Centre (DLR), Institute of Radar Systems, from 1998 to 2001 as a Member of Scientific Staff in the Radar Digital Signal Processing Department; at the European Aeronautic Defense and Space Company &amp;ndash; EADS from 2001 to 2003 as external technical consultant; at INTRACOM Defense Electronics from 2003 to 2006 as Product Marketing Engineer; and from 2006 to 2008 as Senior Manager at Epicos S.A. Since September 2008, Dr. Potsis has held the position of Senior Manager in the European Finance Associates Group of Companies, where he is responsible for the development of new business opportunities in the defence market in Greece and globally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Potsis becane the first president of the Hellenic Association of Space Industries in 2009.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;athanassios-skodras-chairman-elections-committee:8e1b4e6891b85468515b3e2b8f66201a&#34;&gt;Athanassios Skodras &amp;ndash; Chairman, Elections Committee&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/board_members/skodras.png&#34; alt=&#34;Athanassios Skodras&#34; title=&#34;Athanassios Skodras&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Athanassios N. Skodras received a BSc degree in Physics from Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, Greece, and MEng in Computer Engineering &amp;amp; Informatics and PhD in Electronics from University of Patras, Greece. Since 1986 he has been holding teaching and research positions at the Departments of Physics and Computer Engineering &amp;amp; Informatics of the University of Patras, and the Research Academic Computer Technology Institute, Patras. As of October 2002 he is Professor of Digital Systems and Head of Computer Science, School of Science and Technology, Hellenic Open University, Patras, Greece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Skodras serves as an Associate Editor for the IEEE Signal Processing Letters, the Pattern Recognition and the Springer Journal Of Real-Time Image Processing, Vice Chair of the IEEE Greece Section, Chair of the IEEE Greece CAS &amp;amp; SSC Chapters, Chair of the Greek Association of Image Processing and Digital Media, and is the Technical Coordinator of the WG6 on image and video coding of the Greek Organization for Standardization. He has also served as the General Chair of the 16th IEEE Int. Conference on Digital Signal Processing and as the co-Chair of the 14th IEEE Int. Conference on Digital Signal Processing, and the Technical Program Committee Chair of the 13th IEEE Int. Conference on Digital Signal Processing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Skodras is a Chartered Engineer, Senior Member of the IEEE, and member of the IET, EURASIP and the Technical Chamber of Greece.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://www.gsa-hsa.github.io/posts/contact-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 16:53:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gsa-hsa.github.io/posts/contact-us/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Greek Space Agency&lt;br /&gt;
Information Technologies Institute&lt;br /&gt;
Centre of Research &amp;amp; Technology - Hellas&lt;br /&gt;
6th km Harilaou - Thermi&lt;br /&gt;
P.O. Box 60361&lt;br /&gt;
Thessaloniki 57001,&lt;br /&gt;
Greece&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=40.5667611,22.9980147&amp;amp;zoom=13&amp;amp;size=600x400&amp;amp;maptype=roadmap&amp;amp;markers=color:red%7Clabel:S%7C40.5667611,22.9980147&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Map&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Conference on Space Technology (ICST)</title>
      <link>http://www.gsa-hsa.github.io/posts/icst/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 16:53:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gsa-hsa.github.io/posts/icst/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/icst_logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;I.C.S.T. logo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The proliferation of micro-satellites has made space affordable and accessible to many people. Space technology, therefore, spans a broad area of research and development, from electronic components for satellites to intelligent systems for on-board data analysis. Most of the satellites face the Earth rather than the outer space. From home electricity meter readings to disaster monitoring, surveillance and crop forecast, satellites play a very important role in our daily lives. It has also become increasingly important for signal/image processing researchers and intelligent systems to consider the whole pipeline of data collection, data processing, and conclusions drawing rather than try to solve individual problems in isolation. For example, there is no point in developing intelligent robotic systems to operate on-board a satellite if these systems rely on resources well beyond what one can place on a satellite; and there is little purpose to developing intelligent systems for early fire detection from space if the orbit of the satellite is not designed to allow frequent coverage of the monitored area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ICST is designed to bring together people who work on different aspects of space technology research to facilitate and enhance the interactions along this chain of activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conference details coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>http://www.gsa-hsa.github.io/posts/privacy-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 16:53:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gsa-hsa.github.io/posts/privacy-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Greek Space Agency website does not automatically gather any specific personal information from you, such as your name, phone number or email address. We would only obtain this type of information if you supply it by sending us an email or registering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will always be asked for consent to collect your personally identifiable information, and you will be informed of the purpose for which it is being collected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not use personal information you provide us with to create individual profiles, nor do we sell, trade or otherwise transfer your personally identifiable information to outside parties. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us with in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, or protect ours or others&amp;rsquo; rights, property or safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include link to third parties on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content or activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our sites and therefore welcome your feedback about such sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By using our site you consent to our privacy policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we decided to change our privacy, any and all changes will be posted on this page. The privacy policy was last modified on Nov.20/09.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions or comments regarding this policy may be directed to: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:privacy.policy@gsa-hsa.com&#34; title=&#34;Email regarding privacy policy&#34;&gt;privacy.policy@gsa-hsa.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://www.gsa-hsa.github.io/posts/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 16:53:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gsa-hsa.github.io/posts/projects/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;GSA supports and facilitates international projects and collaborations with space agencies around the globe while supporting local industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GSA is currently engaged in establishing an international information processing centre, to be operated by a multi-national industry-government body, complete with cutting-edge technology, a highly skilled team of remote sensing researchers and the expertise of leading academic institutions and companies from around the world. The Multi-Sensor Information processing Centre (MSIC) will be designed to satisfy the needs of various end users, including governments and the private sector. Cost-effective, precise, timely satellite data is in high demand by a multitude of markets, anything from urban planning, environmental monitoring, agriculture, oil and gas industry, and infrastructure mapping, to intelligence, emergency response planning, and visual simulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multiple companies, other space agencies and companies will offer satellite data, tools, and applications that are approved by the MSIC board, and serve only the applications that fall within the mandate of GSA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GSA welcomes the scientific communities of Greece and worldwide to actively participate in the development of MSIC. For additional information, please contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:msic@gsa-hsa.com&#34; title=&#34;Email MSIC&#34;&gt;msic@gsa-hsa.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;projects-eligible-for-gsa-support:3c42bb4157bf51d85ae7ffc4e1685909&#34;&gt;Projects Eligible for GSA Support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only multi-national studies featuring scientists from different national space agencies, industry, universities and government labs qualify for GSA support. A project is considered multinational if participants from 4 or more countries, including Greece, are engaged. The project must fit under GSA&amp;rsquo;s mandate and illustrate clear benefits for both the project participants and around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;call-for-proposals:3c42bb4157bf51d85ae7ffc4e1685909&#34;&gt;Call for Proposals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GSA holds an annual call for proposal. Expressions of interest are reviewed by the GSA board, with only the most viable mission/project concepts chosen. GSA assists the selected proponents to receive the required financing, either wholly or partially, depending on project&amp;rsquo;s nature and scope.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.gsa-hsa.github.io/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gsa-hsa.github.io/posts/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;exploring-the-cosmos:d680e8a854a7cbad6d490c445cba2eba&#34;&gt;Exploring the Cosmos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/main/GSA1.png&#34; alt=&#34;galaxy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From space travel to space technology development, GSA has been founded to advance Greece’s participation in space exploration. Space technology development and application are becoming increasingly central to economic, industrial and social prosperity of nations worldwide. GSA is a private, non-profit organization that promotes, via a variety of forums and international programs and missions, scientific and technological breakthroughs to be benefited by all Greek citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is the GSA’s goal to ensure that Greece once again regains its role as a leader in space exploration activities and the study of the solar system and deep space, via international collaborations with scientists, space programs and agencies around Europe and across the globe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;space-exploration:d680e8a854a7cbad6d490c445cba2eba&#34;&gt;Space Exploration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I suppose we shall soon travel by air-vessels; make air instead of sea voyages; and at length find our way to the Moon, in spite of the want of atmosphere.”&lt;br /&gt;
— Lord Byron, 1882&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ancient Greek astronomers have laid the foundations of scientific astronomy. By applying logical and geometric observations, they recognized that the moon revolves around the Earth and the Earth revolves around the sun, calculated the size of the Earth, and figured out it was round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Everything has a natural explanation. The moon is not a god, but a great rock, and the sun a hot rock.”&lt;br /&gt;
—Anaxagoras, 5th century BC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pythagoras, Thales, Anaxagoras, Heracleides, Aristarchus, Hipparchus and Ptolemy were among the early scientists to attempt to define the stellar world and develop an understanding of the Earth and our solar system; Greek satirist Lucian wrote about an imaginary voyage to the moon in the 2nd century AD. Space travel, however, remained science fiction until the 20th century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It is complete nonsense to believe flying machines will ever work.”&lt;br /&gt;
— Sir Stanley Mosley, 1905&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-brief-history-of-space-travel:d680e8a854a7cbad6d490c445cba2eba&#34;&gt;A Brief History of Space Travel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Date&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Event&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;October 4, 1957&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Soviet Union launches Sputnik 1, the world’s first artificial satellite&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;January 2, 1959&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Luna 1, first man-made satellite to orbit the sun, is launched by the USSR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;April 1, 1960&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tiros 1, the first successful weather satellite, is launched by the US&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;April 12, 1961&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Soviet Cosmonaut Yuri Gagarin becomes the first human to enter space and return safely on Vostok 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;March 18, 1965&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Soviet Cosmonaut Alexei A. Leonov performs the first space walk, lasting 12 minutes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;July 20, 1969&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;USA’s Neil Armstrong becomes the first man to walk on the moon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;December 15, 1970&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Soviet Venera 7 is the first probe to soft-land on Venus&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;April 19, 1971&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Salyut 1 space station is launched by the USSR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;November 13, 1971&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;American Mariner 9 becomes the first spacecraft to orbit another planet: Mars. Over the next year, it maps 100% of the Martian surface&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;March 2, 1972&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Launch of unmanned Pioneer 10: first space probe to an outer planet, the first spacecraft to travel through the asteroid belt, the first spacecraft to make direct observations and obtain close-up images of Jupiter, and the first man-made object to leave the solar system&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;December, 1972&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Scientists designate Cignus X-1 as the first probable black hole&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;November 3, 1973&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;American Mariner 10 is launched; over the next year, it returns photographs of Venus and Mercury&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;September 3, 1976&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Viking 2 lands on Mars&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;September 1, 1979&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pioneer 11 reaches Saturn, flying to within 13,000 miles and taking the first close-up photographs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;July 2, 1985&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;European Space Agency launches the Giotto spacecraft, which encounters Halley&amp;rsquo;s Comet in 1986, and Comet P/Grigg-Skjellerup in 1992&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;January, 1986&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Voyager 2 flies past Uranus&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;April 24, 1990&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Space Shuttle Discovery deploys the Edwin P. Hubble Space Telescope astronomical observatory – the first space-based optical telescope that confirms an expanding universe&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;March 31, 1997&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;After 25 years of operation, routine telemetry and ground control with Pioneer 10 is terminated, with Pioneer 10 being 6.7 billion miles from Earth, traveling at 28,000 miles per hour&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new millennium saw a new trend of privately funded space-exploration. The year 2000 was host to the first commercial human spaceflight, followed by the beginning of the era of space tourism shortly thereafter (2001).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We&amp;rsquo;ll go into orbit. We&amp;rsquo;ll go to the Moon. This business has no limits.”&lt;br /&gt;
— Richard Branson, Virgin Galactic, January 2005&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We welcome feedback and content suggestions; to comment on the website, or suggest/provide content (including multimedia content) to be placed on the GSA website, please email &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:web@gsa-hsa.com&#34; title=&#34;Email webmaster&#34;&gt;web@gsa-hsa.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>